Sieder Villareal

React Developer

Uptown Parksuites, Tower 1, 8th Ave, Taguig, Philippines (63) 9178752601 siedervillareal@gmail.com

SKILLS

A position in the IT industry which would allow me to contribute to the success of an organization through the knowledge and experience that I have gained: improve the existing applications and develop new software solutions, enhance my programming and analytical skills.

EXPERIENCE

AirAsia Philippines, Inc, Makati, Philippines - Senior Software Engineer

November 2022 - Current

- Develop & contributed on food delivery, dine-in, dutyfree, hotels app -AirAsia
- Use Reactis/React Native technology for frontend development
- Redux/Sagas Toolkit for state management
- Daily use of git, review codes before merging
- Daily SCRUM, confluence, gitlab
- Leveraged AstroJS to architect hybrid rendering (SSG, SSR, CSR) for optimal performance, SEO, and dynamic interactivity across web applications

Indra Philippines, Inc, Pasig, Philippines - Fullstack Developer

October 2021 - November 2022

- Develop back office app AirAsia
- Use Reactjs/React Native technology for frontend development
- Redux Toolkit for state management
- Nodejs backend
- Daily use of git, review codes before merging
- Daily SCRUM, confluence, gitlab

Indra Philippines, Inc., Pasig, Philippines - Fullstack Developer

December 2019 - January 2021

- Develop OurDaily app AirAsia (airasia.com/explore)
- Use Reactjs technology for frontend development
- Use linting & Jest/Enzyme for frontend testing

- Nodejs backend & mocha for testing
- Daily use of git, review codes before merging
- Daily SCRUM, confluence, gitlab

Jump Digital Asia Pte. Ltd, Pasig, Philippines - Web Engineer

July 2018 - April 2019

- Reactjs for frontend development
- Implementing GraphQL with back-end technology
- Building web applications using Ruby on Rails
- Developing applications using Python 3.7 with Django 2.1 framework
- Database creation and administration with MySQL server
- Used React.js for front-end web development (ES6)
- Setting up cloud server with Linode
- Installs and configures Linux operating systems(Ubuntu16.04, Debian 9, CentOS 7)
- Configuring web servers (Apache, nginx)
- Setting up SSL certificate for unsecured websites

Ministry Of Municipality & Environment(CGIS), Qatar - 4th Line

Technical Support / System Admin

November 2015 - February 2018

- Supporting user's software configuration and applications.
- Assemble PC's for users and install operating system they prefer, setup network and administration permissions.
- Windows 2012 Administration, Active Directory, and Troubleshooting.
- Oracle Solaris 11.3 Administration
- Designing technical diagrams for the CGIS infrastructure, focused on Unix servers.
- Oracle 12c Administration, giving permissions, creating users and upgrading to newer patch.
- SAN Operator, creating LUNs(Logical Unit Number) and file servers.
- Monitoring servers using Oracle Cloud Control 13c, installed in Oracle Linux 6.5.
- HPE Data Protector (Backup Operator).
- Programming a simple Content Management System with MySQL/Oracle as Database or any other database they prefer.
- Managing license server for AutoCAD Licenses.
- Daily coordination with stakeholders(Government Agencies) on fixing client connectivity to our Unix Server.

Ooredoo - Connections MIddle-east, Qatar - Fiber Optic OSP Network Supervisor

October 2012 - October 2014

- Supervising and coordinating subcontracted service provider's deliveries with regard to outside plant construction civil work activities and required fiber optic installation/termination, ensuring the project is delivering on scope, cost and time.
- Monitoring, managing and reporting subcontractor's performance against project targets.

- Organizing and performing civil work quality audits as appropriate; identify, make recommendations and follow up on improving the quality and performance of the subcontractor's workmanship during the project rollout.
- Managing daily communication, being a point of contact for SP for queries, change requests and issue resolution in construction phase of the pilot.
- Establish and agree objectives and targets for In Building Cabling program.
- Supervise contractors during OSP related works, Inspection after completion of the project.
- Define the standards and specifications to govern the deployment.
- Manage development and agreement of business cases to support program budgets and objectives.
- Manage coordination with Commercial team to deliver Landlord agreements to deploy, integrate, inspect, and test in building cabling.
- Manage relationships with all internal and external stakeholders required to define and deliver the program.
- Manages contract and/or employee fiber splicers. Provides on the job divisional training to contractors to ensure the proper method and procedures of facility protection and maintenance are followed. This includes the use of locating equipment, use of Optical Time Domain Reflectometers (OTDR) and troubleshooting tone generation/reception in field.
- Maintains the security of the outside fiber plant (OSP) network, throughout area of responsibility by managing cable location, by locating contractors and initiating protection activities. Works closely with other carriers, local/ state agencies and building owners/landlords on new building adds and relocations.

QTEL(Qatar Telecom) - Connections MIddle-east, Qatar - Fiber Optic Support

June 2010 - September 2012

- Receive work orders from Work Order Control, sort the work orders by unit wise, enter work order details in cable system and distribute the work orders to concerned Engineers.
- Prepare BOQ (Bill of Quantities) for quotation, type necessary RFQ (Request For Quotation) etc. in coordination with concerned engineers
- Assist field supervisors for checking ODF (Optical Distribution Frame) details, taking necessary printouts from TELECORDIA/GIS Web.
- After completion of each work order, scan the related diagrams and attach the scanned copy to server. Send completion report to all concerned Department (Planning Section).
- Daily updates for Qtel systems like remedy, CRM, TELECORDIA, Cable system or any other systems required or the smooth & efficient execution of fiber optic works.
- Prepare RE/WO documents related to fiber optic cable damages.
- Follow up with Qtel Purchasing/Contract section and after the approval of final PO, forward the work order to concerned Engineer for raising GRN in system.

• Update cable system regularly in coordination with supervisors.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science (Honors) in Business Information Systems

University of Portsmouth, United Kingdom June 2017 - November 2018

Advanced Diploma in Software Engineering

APTECH Computer Education Center, Qatar
December 2009 - September 2010

Professional Diploma in Software Engineering

APTECH Computer Education Center, Qatar January 2009 - November 2009

Higher Diploma in Software Engineering

APTECH Computer Education Center, Qatar August 2006 - August 2007

Diploma in Information Systems & Management

APTECH Computer Education Center, Qatar August 2006 - August 2007

High School Diploma

Philippine International School Qatar, Qatar June 2001 - March 2005

Trainings Attended

Oracle University Private Classroom Trainings - 2017

- Oracle Solaris 11 System Administration Ed 5 PRV
- Oracle Solaris 11 Advanced System Administration Ed 5 PRV
- Oracle Enterprise Manager Cloud Control 13c: Install & Upgrade Ed 1 PRV
- Using Oracle Enterprise Manager Cloud Control 13c Ed 1 PRV
- Oracle Database 12c: ASM Administration
- Oracle Database 12c: Administration Workshop Ed 2

- Oracle Database 12c: Cluster-ware Administration
- Oracle Database 12c: RAC Administration Ed 1

Trainings Attended from Ministry of Municipality & Environment

- Implementing Desktop Application Environments (Windows Server 2012)
- Understanding Microsoft Products Licensing
- Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3
- SQL Database for Oracle Administrators
- Installing and Configuring System Center 2012 Operations Manager
- Programming in C#
- Essentials of Developing Windows Store Apps Using C#
- System Center Operations Manager 2012
- System Center Service Manager 2012
- Administering Microsoft Exchange Server 2016
- Designing and Deploying Microsoft Exchange Server 2016.

References

Pablo Barbero +639989662824 | pbarberoc@indracompany.com Indra Philippines, inc - Manager

Marie Noriele Ani +639173010469 | mn.ani@jumpdigital.asia Jump Digital Asia - Tech/Innovation Project Manager

Jameela Salman Ahmad Alamri +97455540877 | jameela@gisqatar.org.qa Minstry of Municipality & Environment(CGIS) - IT Manager